Today we are here to worship Shri Krishna.
我們今天在這裏敬拜克里希納
As you know Shri Krishna is the incarnation of Vishnu.
你們都知道，克里希納是毗濕奴的轉世
And Vishnu is the one who is the preserver of this universe.
毗濕奴是宇宙的持守者
When this whole world was created
世界被創造之際
it was necessary
必須也
to create a preserver also
創造一個持守者
because this world would have been destroyed
若沒有持守者
and completely if it is left alone without a preserver,
世界便會受完全的摧毀
then the way human beings are,
人類就是這樣
they could have done anything to this world.
他們對世界可以做出任何事
But so, Vishnu is the preserver.
毗濕奴是持守者，祂不單是持守者
He's the preserver and He's the only one really incarnates.
還是唯一以祂原本的形相降世的神祇
Of course,
當然
sometimes Brahmadeva also incarnated,
梵天婆羅摩有時也會降世
but He only takes forms.
但祂卻以不同的形相降世
In our evolutionary process He has taken different forms.
在進化的過程中，祂以不同的形相
He came on this earth in different ways.
不同的途徑來到地球
But still He had, as you say,
但祂仍然，正如你所說
twelve
十二
up to twelve was Shri Rama and up through ten He was there.
錫呂‧羅摩到達十二，祂實際上在十已經存在
So He created also an atmosphere of the many great prophets
祂創造合適的環境，讓很多偉大的先知
around Himself so that they could preserve the dharma
圍繞祂，因此他們可以
of this universe.
保存宇宙的正法
So the basis of preservation was dharma,
保存的基礎是正法
which has got, as you know,
你們都知道
the most important basic foundation for spiritual life.
這是靈性生活最重要、最基本的基礎
In this dharma whatever was to be established
在正法中，若有甚麽一定要建立
was to be established balance.
那必定是平衡
Was a habit with people to go to extremes in anything.
人們慣於走向極端
So He created a balance within us.
所以祂在我們內裏建立平衡
The first principal of dharma was to create balance.
正法的第一個原則是平衡
If a person doesn't have a balance
若沒有平衡
then he cannot achieve his ascent.
人類便不能昇進
As simple as that.
就是這樣簡單
If you don't have a balance in your airplane it cannot ascend.
若飛機失去平衡，便飛不了
If you don't have a balance, say on a ship, it won't move.
若人沒有平衡，就如一艘船，不能動
In the same way,
同樣
first the human beings had to achieve the balance.
人類首先要平衡
But they are born with different capacities,
每個人自出生以來，就有不同的才能
with different capabilities.
不同的能力
As said that, "Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu Jhati rupena samstita",
我說︰「Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu Jhati rupena samstita」
means the aptitudes are different.
意思是天資不同
They are born with different aptitudes,
他們出生時已經擁有不同的資質
with different faces, with different colors,
不同面孔，不同膚色
because variety was to be created.
這是為了創造多樣化
If everybody looked the same, you see they would be looking
若每個人都是一模一樣
like some robots or something.
他們便像機械人
So everybody was created in a different way,
把每個人創造成不同的模樣
according to the country,
依照他們的國家
according to the parents.
他們的父母
All this was organized by the principal of Shri Vishnu,
這些都是錫呂‧毗濕奴原則掌管的
that He created this world in different varieties.
祂創造多樣化的世界
He gave variety, and Shri Krishna is the master of it.
是祂賜予多樣化，錫呂‧克里希納則是主管人
At the time when Shri Krishna came,
克里希納降臨的時代
people were extremely serious type
人類是極之嚴肅
and had become very ritualistic.
極之儀式化
The reason was that Rama came and He talked of maryadas,
原因是因為羅摩降臨，祂談論份際(maryadas)
and these maryadas made people extremely,
份際令人
extremely austere type.
極之苦行
In that austerity people lost the sense of joy,
這種苦行的人，失去了喜樂
sense of beauty, sense of variety.
失去了漂亮，失去了多樣化
So the Shri Krishna's incarnation
錫呂‧克里希納因此降世
came as we call it the Sampurna,
我們稱為sampurna
it's complete because He has 16 petals.
祂是完全的，因為祂擁有16片花瓣
As the moon has 16 kalas He too had 16 petals
月亮有16個kalas，祂也有16片花瓣
so He's Sampurna and He is what we call is the Purnima,
所以祂是sampurna。祂就是我們稱呼的purnima
is the full moon.
即盈月
With this completeness of His incarnation,
祂的降世是完全的
of Vishnu's incarnation from Vishnu to many other incarnations
從毗濕奴的降世，到很多其他的降世神祇
He came as the complete incarnation;
祂以祂完全的形相降世
the total of Shri Vishnu was manifested.
錫呂‧毗濕奴完全彰顯
So whatever was lacking in Rama's incarnation,
若羅摩的降世有任何缺乏
He brought it forth.
是克里希納作出補足
As you know that on the center - on the right heart
你們都知道在中央，在右心輪
you have twelve petals.
有十二片花瓣
With this He showed so many things
因此，祂顯示很多
which people miss completely,
別人完全錯失的東西
because, unfortunately, Gita was written down.
很不幸，薄伽梵歌有記錄
When Gita was written down,
因為薄伽梵歌有記錄
people started following the book word by word, not understanding.
人們不去理解，卻一字一句的遵從
And in the Gita His message was never for peace.
在薄伽梵歌，祂的信息從來不是和平
He didn't say you should be peaceful.
祂沒有說你要平和
It was something like Jihad.
就像Jihad對亞周那說
That He said that to Arjuna, "You have to fight.
你必須作戰
At this time you have to fight for dharma,
這時候，你要為正法
for the truth and you have to fight."
為真理作戰，你必須抗爭
Then He said, "I can't kill my uncles
亞周那答︰「我不能殺害我的叔父
and I can't kill my grandfather and I can't kill my relations."
我的祖父，我的所有親人。」
He said, "Who, who are you killing, they're already dead."
他說︰「他們是誰？你在殺害誰？他們已經死了。」
Because they have no dharma.
因為他們沒有正法
If you have no dharma then you are already dead.
若沒有正法，你便是死人
So what is there to kill or not to kill
所以你在殺害誰
and that is what today we see in modern times,
這是我們現代看到的
especially America which is the country of Vishuddhi.
特別是美國，這個代表喉輪的國家
They have no dharma so they're already dead
他們沒有正法
under dope or whatever you may call it,
因為毒品，或無論你怎樣稱呼它
under fear of all kinds of diseases.
因為對各種疾病的恐懼
They are already dead and whom are you going to kill?
他們已經死了。既然他們已經死了，你又在殺害誰呢？
And this message was in Kurukshetra He gave to Arjuna.
這信息是祂在Khurukshetra傳達給亞周那的
But then he said, "You have asked me to kill these people
跟著祂說︰「你請求我去殺死這些人
because I have Dharma in me. I am killing them, alright,
因為我內在有正法，我要殺死他們，好吧
but what beyond this?"
除了這些，還有甚麽？」
What is beyond that?
甚麽是超越這些？
So He describes Sahaja Yoga.
祂描繪霎哈嘉瑜伽
Beyond this was Sahaja Yoga.
超越這些是霎哈嘉瑜伽
Was, first He describes in the second chapter
首先，他在第二章
who is the Stitha Pragya,
描繪誰是Stita pragya
is the man who is balanced.
即平衡的人
Then he says that such a man is never angry.
他說這類人不會生氣
He doesn't get angry.
不會發怒
Inside he is absolutely at peace.
內在絕對的平和
So what He described later on is really the modern times,
他跟著描述的是真正的現代
or we can say our Sahaja Yoga
我們可以說是霎哈嘉瑜伽
in which He said how a person should become.
祂在說人必須要變成怎樣
He didn't write, or He didn't say how to become that,
他沒有把這些記錄下來，也沒有說該怎樣做才能變成這樣
but the description is just like Christ I think where He says that
他描繪的正正是基督
if you somebody slaps you on one face you put the
基督說，若有人打你一邊面，你的另一邊面
other side of the face.
也要給他打
All this is actually description of Sahaja Yogis
所有這些，正正就是未來的
of the future.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Not at that time when Khauravas were fighting the Pandavas.
不是Khauravas與Pandavas作戰那個時候
It was not at that time.
不是那個時候
During that fight He told him
在戰場裏，他告訴他
that if you become a Stitha Pragya then you can transcend
若你變成Stita pragya，便可以
all these problems,
超越這些問題
all these understandings that you have,
這些誤解
and you become absolutely peaceful with yourself.
變得完全的平和
So on one side He said you have to fight.
一方面，他說你要作戰
Now in modern times we do not have to fight Kauravas,
在現代我們不用與Khauravas作戰
there are no Kauravas
沒有Khauravas
The five Pandavas have to fight the Khauravas.
但五位Pandavas必須與Khauravas作戰
So now what are these five Pandavas?
現在，這五位Pandavas是甚麽？
They are our senses
是我們的感官
or we can call they are the cosmos,
也可以稱它們是分裂成
divided into various elements.
不同元素的宇宙
One side. They have to fight,
他們必須作戰
they have to fight the Kauravas
與我們內在的
which are within us.
Khauravas作戰
Now there are hundred Kauravas, not one.
現在卻有成千上萬的Khauravas，不止一個
It is, if you extend it
若你把它伸延，
then we can say the nature has to fight
你也可以說是大自然與
something that is against the nature.
違反大自然作戰
Now people will say anger is natural,
大家說憤怒是自然的
getting annoyed is natural,
受困擾是自然的
to be aggressive is natural.
好勇鬥狠是自然的
It is not.
不是這樣的
Anger and all these things may have been natural,
憤怒以及所有這些或許是自然的
but now we must know that we have the natural capacity to ascend.
但我們必須知道，我們有能耐昇進是自然的
Is natural to go higher.
自然的升進得更高
It is natural to be Stitha pragya.
自然的變成Stita pragya
It is natural to be Sahaja Yogi.
自然的成為霎哈嘉瑜伽士
This is also built in us, in us.
這些全都已經安置在我們內裏
For example a seed is a seed.
例如，種子是種子
When it is seed we call it seed.
它是種子所以我們稱它為種子
Alright, naturally is to be seed,
播放種子是很自然的
but then it sprouts and becomes the tree.
跟著它發芽生長，長成大樹
So it is also natural in a seed
這種生長過程是最自然不過的
that all that future,
成千上萬
all the thousands of trees
的樹木成長
it is going to be is also in that seed.
一切只源於種子
And now as you know they're experimenting that
你們都知道，它們都曾經
in one seed you can get thousand
從小小的種子
minimum of thousands of little, little sprouts in one seed
經過上千次的發芽，
and which can be made all of them into trees or plants.
長成大樹，長成植物
This is a new thing that has come up.
這是新事物，
So when He said that
所以當祂說
you have to become a Stitha pragya
你必須變成Stita pragya
what He was trying to say that you should achieve your balance.
祂在說你必須平衡
Now this He told,
現在祂說
there was a war on.
戰爭持續
When they were warring,
當他們在戰鬥
alright, you have to do it.
好吧，你也必須作戰
If you have to war with people,
你要與人作戰
if you have to kill them it's all right.
若你想殺死他們，也沒有問題
But afterwards,
戰爭
once that is over
結束後
then what you have to do is to build up your spiritual sense.
你要做的是建立靈性
Now the building up of the spiritual sense
我們現在需要做的，
is our work and that's what we have to do.
必須做的工作是建立自己的靈性
Not only dharma.
不單正法
Many Sahaja Yogis think that they are going in dharma
很多霎哈嘉瑜伽士以為他們
so they are alright.
向著正法，便會沒有不妥
They are working in dharma,
他們在正法裏工作
they are living in a dharmic life.
過著正法的生活
They are. I'm very surprised and happy that they are doing it.
他們確是這樣。我很驚訝和高興他們能這樣做
But that's not the end of it.
這不是終結
That's the balance part
這是平衡
where you are balancing yourself.
你在平衡自己
Now, what you have to do is to go ahead
你現在要趕上前
and build up your spiritual self and spread it.
建立靈性，傳播靈性
This is the work of Shri Krishna also
這也是錫呂‧克里希納的工作
because He's the one who communicates all over.
因為祂與各處溝通
As you know America is communicating everywhere
你們都知道，美國與每一處地方溝通
in a wrong way - but it is.
雖然以錯誤的方式
It has got computers,
它擁有電腦
it has got this,
擁有各種
all communication things it has done
溝通的工具
because it is innately built in them to communicate.
它的溝通能力是天生賦予的
But because they don't believe in Shri Krishna,
他們不相信錫呂‧克里希納
neither in dharma,
亦不相信正法
so the basis itself is wrong,
所以它在錯誤的基礎上
and with this wrong basis they have started spreading.
以這錯誤的基礎，他們開始傳播
With this very, very wrong basis
以這非常非常錯誤的基礎
they have started spreading ah,
他們開始傳播
all kinds of filth and dirt and I don't know what to call it,
各種污穢骯髒的事物，我也不知道該怎樣稱呼它們
which is against human beings,
那是違反人性
which is against our ascent,
違反昇進
which is against God.
違反神
And they are doing all this.
他們卻在做著這些事情
Why?
為甚麽？
Why are they doing which they are not supposed to do?
為甚麽他們要做一些不該做的事情？
I think is the intellect.
我想是思維能力(intellect)
Their intellect which is also,
也是他們的聰明才智
I should say is the brain, which is the seat of Virat.
我應該說這是腦袋，那是宇宙大我的寶座
Can you imagine? Is the seat of Virat.
你可以想像嗎？是宇宙大我的寶座
And with their intellect, what do they do?
以他們的聰明才智，他們做了些甚麽？
They say it is natural.
他們說這是自然的
It is natural to be adharmic.
自然的不正法
It is natural to be aggressive.
自然的好勇鬥狠
It is natural to be money oriented.
自然的金錢取向
Everything that they have is all natural
他們能擁有一切都是自然的
because according to them
因為他們認為
with their intellect they have somehow or other managed
憑自己的聰明才智
to convince through your rationality
想以理性去說服你
that this is the correct thing to do.
這是正確的事情
Without this you cannot exist.
若不這樣，你是不能存在
I mean this is supposed to be their culture now.
我的意思是現在這些都變成他們的文化
Now if that is the culture all over,
若這是文化
it's not only in America all over,
不單是美國的文化
this sort of a nonsensical culture
因為聰明
is accepted because of the intellect.
大家都接受這種荒唐的文化
They are much more intelligent.
他們是更加聰明
You see a person who always thinks of money, this, that,
你見到時刻都想著金錢的人
naturally becomes very intelligent
他們很自然的變得非常聰明
in the sense he becomes sharp.
某程度上變得尖銳
He becomes smart.
變得精明
something as if he knows everything.
就像他知道一切
He starts thinking he knows everything,
以為自己知道一切
whatever he's doing he is right,
他做的任何事
whatever the way he is behaving he is right.
任何行為都是對的
So, these Pandavas which he has got within himself,
所以，他內在的Pandavas
these elements that he has got,
他擁有的元素
he uses them for a purpose
全都用在
which is destructive,
毀滅
absolutely destructive - anti God.
完全的毀滅，反對神的用途上
And he is not aware
他意識不到這些
because his intelligence always justifies.
因為他的思維力量常常為他辯護
Whatever he's doing is justified.
他做的任何事，都是正確的
And He has given also so much of brains to these intellectuals
祂賜予智力超群的人太多聰明才智
that they also try to go against what is dharma.
他們卻違反正法
For example, even Shri Krishna's life
打個比方，就連錫呂‧克里希納
they try to depict by saying
他們也這樣描繪︰
that Shri Krishna Himself had five wives
錫呂‧克里希納有5個妻子
and He had sixteen wives later on.
之後祂有16個妻子
Actually these were His power.
實際上祂的妻子是祂的力量
But without understanding what Shri Krishna was,
若不理解錫呂‧克里希納
because intellect is such a gross nonsense
你的聰明便很粗淺兼荒唐
that it doesn't take you to the right thinking;
不能令你有正確的思維
always to the wrong thinking,
也常常誤導你
it moves you because you want to justify
它推動你是因為你想對一切辯護
everything and this justification
這種辯護令你只活在
makes you live with yourself.
自己的世界裏
Otherwise, normally,
若不是這樣
you can't live with yourself.
通常你與自己是
It is very difficult to live
相處不來的
with a life which is adharmic,
過著不正法
which is aggressive,
好勇鬥狠
which is, what you can call,
又或你稱為
a war mongering type.
製造戰爭型的生活是很困難的
But they live.
但他們卻能過這種生活
So, all that is expected of a human being,
我對人類的期望
just the opposite of that,
卻是與此完全相反的
juxtaposition of that,
與此並列的
is being done in all these western cultures.
是西方文化
You can see it clearly how they justify.
你看到他們是怎樣為自己辯護
Immorality they can justify.
為不道德辯護
One Mr. Freud came in.
當佛洛依德出現
He replaced even Christ.
他甚至取代基督
Of course, I mean, he had to because Christ was even more
當然，我的意思是，他必須要這樣
strict than Mohammed sahib
因為基督比穆罕默德還嚴肅
who said anybody does anything with one eye,
祂說若任何人的眼睛犯錯
with the eyes, he should take out one eye,
必須挖去這隻眼睛
and anybody who's hand is spoiling him should,
任何人的手犯錯
he should cut his hand.
要切去這隻手
I mean most of the Europeans and Americans
我的意思是，若按基督的話
would have been without one hand I think,
大部分歐洲人和美國人
according to Christ.
都是沒有手的
Thank God they didn't follow Him to that point.
感謝神，他們在這方面沒有跟隨基督
And, also Mohammed sahib thought
穆罕默德認為
that Christ has done so much for the men,
基督為男人做了很多事
why not we do something for the women also,
為甚麽不為女人也做點事
so He made something for women.
所以祂為女士做了點事
Both of them are too much for human beings.
祂們兩位對人類都太嚴厲了
They didn't realize it.
他們卻意識不到
Who's going to take out one eye for that?
誰會為此挖去一隻眼睛？
They have intellect.
他們擁有聰明才智
Now, if they are looking at many women,
現在若他們看著婦女
there's a justification - is natural.
他們的辯解是，這是自然不過的事
Have you seen any animal behaving like that
若畜牲是自然的存有
if the animals are natural beings?
你有否看過畜牲有這種行為？
We are worse than animals.
我們比畜牲更差
And what a mess we have created with this kind of understanding
通過這種智力來理解事情
through these intellectuals
我們製造了怎樣的混亂
who are trying to tell us something, and we accept.
聰明人告訴我們甚麽，我們都接受
So this is one of the problems
那是其中的一個問題
is if there's an intelligent man, he dominates.
聰明人的問題是他好支配人
Now, for example, some fashion starts.
就如現在，一些潮流開始
We all take it.
我們接受
It's a fashion.
這是潮流
But why are you taking it? It's a fashion.
你為甚麽要接受？因為這是潮流
So, the intellect of an entrepreneur
你被企業家的生意頭腦
can really befool you completely.
完全愚弄
But not with people who are wise.
這對有智慧的人是不會起作用的
They will say, "Get lost, we have had all this."
他們會說︰「走開，我們曾經聽說過這些。」
This is about morality part.
這是關乎道德
That is the worst practiced in the West,
這是西方最差勁的習性
and worse than animals I should say.
我必須說
And that's how they are suffering today.
比畜牲更差
They are suffering with so many diseases,
這就是他們為甚麽仍在受苦，受很多疾病
so many troubles, this, that.
很多麻煩，各種事情的苦
Second thing which we always justify is violence.
第二種我們常常自我辯護的是暴力
Now there is no war going on in Kurukshetra.
雖然現在的kurukshetra沒有戰爭
But you see violence everywhere.
你卻看到四處都是暴力
In America it's terrible.
在美國是很可怕
When my daughter went she took out all her ornaments,
當我的女兒到達美國，她脫下所有飾物
put it with Me.
把飾物給我
She said, "Mummy, I can't carry this."
她說︰「媽媽，我不能配戴飾物。」
Nothing was given to the girl.
沒有甚麽是可以給女孩的
All artificial things were given
只有人造的物品
because you can be killed for it.
不然人們會為此殺掉你
I'm not saying it's only in America. It's everywhere.
我不單說在美國，在每一處都是
Because everybody's guru is America.
因為美國是每個人的導師
It starts from America,
從美國開始
the gurudom and people just follow blindly.
導師制度是從美國開始，人們只是盲目的跟隨
So the violence is now entering into our films,
他們把暴力帶入電影
Indian films also, but now they have taken some objection.
印度電影也是，雖然現在他們有點抗拒
Maybe it is too much for us.
或許這對我們是太過份了
But this kind of thing that
你可以殺死任何人的
you can kill anybody,
這種念頭
so if you go on like this,
若持續下去
you see if that is the criteria of greatness
若這是偉大的準則
then Rwanda people should be placed highest
那麽在進化中
in the evolutionary process.
盧安達人必定是位於最高位置
Killing somebody is not allowed. Thou shalt not kill.
殺人是不容許的，我們不能殺人
Muslims are killing.
但穆斯林卻在殺人
Everbody's killing everyone.
每個人都互相殺戮
The other day they killed a very nice man in India
前幾天，他們在沒有任何原因下
for nothing at all.
在印度殺了一個好人
This idea of aggressiveness
好勇鬥狠這念頭
ultimately takes you to the killing part.
最終為你帶來殺戮
You can't even create one ant.
你卻連一隻螞蟻也沒能力創造
How can you kill human beings like that?
又怎能殺人？
Of course, this killing business
當然，這種殺戮是
is taken to the highest limit,
有極限的
like Hitler believed that he was top of the world.
像希特勒相信他處於世界的高峰
This is same,
這也是一樣
that you just forget what you are
你只是忘了你是誰
and you start assuming through your ego
藉由你的自我
that you are something very great.
你假設自己是很了不起
Also, in Sahaja Yoga I find recently
同樣，在霎哈嘉瑜伽，我發覺最近
there are some people who are saying they're gods,
有人說他們是神
they're deities, everything.
他們是降世神祇，他們是一切
So this ego business
這種自我的行為
is actually taking energy of your intelligence,
實際是在消耗你的聰明才智
and the greatest enemy of a human being is,
人類最大的敵人是
is his intelligence, I think,
他的聰明，原因是
because it's so limited,
聰明是那麽有限的
it is so conditioned,
那麽有制約
and it is so arrogant,
那麽傲慢
and it is so blind.
那麽盲目的
Wisdom is a different thing.
智慧卻完全不同
Wisdom you don't get in colleges,
你不能從學院
schools, universities, nowhere.
學校，大學，任何地方學懂智慧
Where do you get it, the wisdom?
你可以在哪裡獲得智慧？
You get it through your Spirit,
只能藉由你的靈
which gives you a complete idea
它給你對錯的
as to what is right and what is wrong.
完整概念
Whatever is wrong will be accepted by intellect, always.
錯誤的事情，有才智的人常常都會接受
Intellect is not wisdom one must understand.
我們要明白，聰明不代表智慧
They're two things - wisdom and intellect.
這是兩碼子的事----聰明和智慧
Now Krishna was known to be the diplomat.
克里希納公認是外交家
He had Divine diplomacy.
他擁有神聖的外交手腕
That means what?
那是甚麽的意思？
He was very intelligent,
祂非常聰明
no doubt. Without that you can't do.
這是無庸致疑的，沒有聰明，你是不能做到
I've met some people who are very highly placed
我曾經遇過地位很高的人
who don't have much intelligence even,
他們甚至並不怎樣聰明
but I have now seen that this intellect is a dangerous thing.
我現在卻看到這種聰明是非常危險的
So Shri Krishna,
克里希納
He used His intellect.
運用祂的聰明才智
He is all powerful.
祂是很有力量的
Nothing can dominate Him.
沒有甚麽可以控制祂
Even his intellect cannot dominate Him.
就算祂的聰明也不能控制祂
He used His intellect.
祂懂得運用祂的聰明
Difference between the two you should see.
你必須明白兩者的分別
You should be able to use your intellect
你要懂得運用你的聰明
and not to be dominated by your intellect.
而不是聰明控制你
So He used His intellect by which He solved many problems.
祂藉由聰明才智解決很多問題
His whole diplomacy was to use His intellect
祂的外交手腕就是運用祂的聰明才智
and use it for the purpose of Divine.
來達到上天的目的
All the time the Divine in Him
上天常常都幫助祂
was helping Him to use His intellect.
去運用祂的聰明
So the difference is that we are slaves of our intellect
我們與克里希納的分別是，我們是聰明的奴隸
and He is the master of His intellect;
而祂則是聰明的主宰
not only, everything.
祂不單是聰明的主宰，還是一切的主宰
His conditioning He is master,
祂掌管祂的制約
His emotions He is master,
掌管祂的情緒
His body He's the master.
祂的身體
He's master of everything.
祂掌管一切
And when you master it you see your intellect very clearly,
當你掌管一切，你便清楚的看到你的聰明才智
oh, this is what it is suggesting.
啊！理應是如此
This is not.
但不是
This intellect can give you very so-called positive ideas
這種聰明令你有所謂的正面思維
that you are the lord of the whole world.
以為自己是全世界的主人
It's supposed to be positive.
雖然它本應是正面的
Or the same intellect can give you ideas
又或，同一個聰明令你感到
that you are nothing.
你地位低微
This intellect plays on top of you.
聰明在玩弄你
Now you are not to be guided by your intellect,
不應是聰明指引你
but by your wisdom,
應是智慧指引你
as you are Sahaja Yogis.
因為你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
So, you have a very good instrument of feeling it-
你有一件很好的工具去感覺它
through your vibrations you can make out
藉由生命能量，你可以分辨
what is good and what is bad.
甚麽是好，甚麽是壞
And you can see sometimes,
你可以有時看到
as being human beings,
作為人類
there are some intellectual effects also coming in.
你也會受聰明的影響
But with Sahaja Yoga you can judge,
通過霎哈嘉瑜伽，你可以
what is this intellect telling you.
判斷聰明想告訴你甚麽
Because the intellect that you have has come out of what
最主要的是你擁有的聰明是從何而來
is the main thing; should go to the subtle point
必須從精微層面去理解
how this intellect has come to us.
去理解這聰明怎會出現
This intellect has come to us because our brain became,
聰明的出現是因為我們的腦袋
active very soon.
很快變得很活躍
I've seen some children extremely intelligent,
我曾經見過有些孩子極之聰明
but they have no wisdom.
卻沒有智慧
If your - only the brain develops too much,
若你只是腦袋過度發展
could be a mother is a very,
可能是
intelligent woman and,
母親很聰明
father must be very intelligent,
或是父親很聰明
inheritance would be great,
所以他們的孩子
so they get it.
有很好的遺傳
Or maybe the circumstances,
又或是因為環境
like if you are born in a particular country
就像若你在一個特別的國家出生
you suddenly become very intelligent.
忽然你變得非常聰明
I've seen Americans, they read all the time.
我曾經見過一些美國人，他們每時每刻都在閱讀
All the time you see them reading.
每一次遇見他們，他們都在閱讀
Even English they read.
連英文書也不放過
But what is the outcome of all that reading I don't know.
我不知道閱讀可以得到甚麽
Every book they will read.
他們讀每一本書
If you ask them what is a computer, they know the computers,
若你問他們甚麽是電腦，他們懂電腦
this thing, that thing, that thing, all the. . .
他們懂這些，那些，懂一切
I don't know how to even put off my television.
我卻甚至連關電視也不懂
If you ask them about television they will know they'll . . .
若你問他們電視，他們會…
anything you want to know about mechanical things they will know.
任何你想知道的機械問題，他們都懂
Anything about politics they will know,
任何政治問題，他們也懂
who's father was that and they will tell you that,
這人的父親是誰，他們可以告訴你
"No, no, no, no this is like this, this like that."
不，不，不，不，是這樣的，是這樣的
All this is avidya; is not knowledge. It is non-knowledge.
這是無明(avidya)，不是知識，是非知識
So they think they're very intelligent
因為他們懂得一切
because they know everything, about everything.
所以以為自己很聰明
Now, with this intellect,
藉由這種智力
as this consciousness comes in they start creating
這種意識的出現，他們開始創造
very intellectual ideas.
一些非常聰明的玩意
Especially in America I have seen
特別在美國，我見過他們
they have got for children
為孩子製造各式各樣
all kinds of funny things just to extract money.
古怪的玩意，只為榨取金錢
For example, there is a golliwog or something
例如，某些怪物或類似的
which has a birthday.
人生日
Can you imagine?
你可以想像嗎？
A birthday is there and sometimes,
任何生日，有時
you see even the, people have big parties for that.
你甚至看到…大家都為此開盛大的生日會
Then they started, let us have birthday of the dogs,
他們開始想，讓我們為狗做生日
so they are having birthdays of the dogs.
因此有狗的生日會
Anybody who puts ideas into them.
任何人都可以為他們出主意
Then there are organizations
一些機構的人說
where they say, "All right, when you are going to die,
好吧，當你快要死的時候
you tell us what suit you want to wear,
告訴我們你想穿甚麽
what tie you want to wear, what shoes, what clothes,
結怎樣的領結，穿甚麽鞋子，甚麽衣服
then what, in of,
還有
what kind of a coffin you want to go - plastic,
想用怎樣的棺木，膠的
or wood, or this and that." I mean . . .
木的還是其他物料造的。」我的意思是…
So it is to be prescribed
指定到這種程度
to such an extent that some people say,
有人說︰
"Put us in the ice, you see, so we'll be there."
「把我們放在冰塊裏，你看，我們便可以在這裏。」
The worst thing, I think,
我想最差的
especially in Europe, is
特別在歐洲
that they have nicely advertised and marketed
是他們的廣告
the thing of going for a holiday.
宣傳去渡假
So, in Italy supposing a person doesn't go to holiday,
在意大利，若有人沒去渡假
he'll say, "There's a crisis in my life."
他會說︰「我的生活有危機」
"What?" "I couldn't go to holiday."
「為甚麽？」「我不能去渡假」。
Then they said you must go there,
跟著他們說你必須渡假
tan your faces,
把臉孔矖黑
stay there in hotels so, so many hotels have come up.
留在酒店裏，很多不同的酒店因此出現
Everybody has to go out.
每一個人都必須出門
Especially I was surprised
我很驚訝的發覺
the whole of Milan is closed for one month.
全米蘭關閉了整整一個月
Nobody you can find there.
甚麽人也找不到
See, I think if they all go and live in jungles
我想他們全都出門了。就算只是住在森林裏
would be a better idea.
也是好的
They will learn much more
在森林學懂的東西
than to waste their time on the seashore.
比浪費時間在海岸多得多
They're spoiling all the seashores.
他們在糟蹋所有的海岸
They have no respect for the sea which is their Father.
對是他們父親的海不尊重
They have no respect for each other.
他們亦沒有互相尊重
The women try to slim down and to look very nice
婦女令自己苗條，外表看來很好
so that they could become nude there.
為的是可以在哪裏裸露身體
The whole industry is so bad.
整個工業都很壞
I mean if, somebody says would you like to come to the seashore,
我的意思是…若有人問你喜不喜歡到海邊去
I would not go.
我就不喜歡
I would hate to go to a place to see so many stupid ladies
我不喜歡到一處很多愚蠢的女人
in the sun busy trying to tan themselves.
在太陽下忙碌的把自己矖成古銅色的地方
Now this stupid idea how could you accept if you are intelligent?
若你是聰明的，你怎會接受這些愚蠢的念頭
There are so many ideas prevalent today,
今天很多流行的玩意
mostly coming from America, I must say,
大部分來自美國。我必須要說，
that you people follow. As I said
大家都追隨。正如我說
that America is the guru of all the Eastern,
美國是所有東方人，
of all our European and English and all these people.
歐洲人，英國人和所有人的靈性導師
Now, then another thing happens.
還有另一件事情在發生
You see the atmosphere in which you live.
你看到你居住的地方的風氣
Especially in England I have noticed.
我注意到特別在英國
They may be nothing, you know.
他們可能不覺得怎樣
There was a garbage cleaner who came to our house
有次有個清潔工來到我的家
and we had that time with us a president
我們正與海牙高等法院的首席法官一起
of the Hague high court, imagine, the world high court.
試想想，全球的最高法院的法官
So, I told him, "You have to clear out all these things."
我告訴清潔工︰「請把這些垃圾倒掉。」
"It's too much!" As usual, you see they are very,
「太多了。」通常都是這樣，你看他們是非常…
I don't know what to say, but, stupidly proud about themselves.
我不知該怎樣說，他們是愚蠢兼驕傲
"You don't understand." I said, "How much do you want?"
我說︰「你不明白嗎，你想要多少錢？」
I gave him ten pounds.
我給他十鎊
In those days ten pounds was a big thing.
那時候的十鎊是很多的錢
He said, "You don't understand the laws,
他說︰「你不懂法律
you see you are all Indians, niggers, this that."
你們都是印度人，都是黑鬼。」
Then this gentleman who was in our house
那位在我家的
he came out and he asked him,
男士走出來問他
"Why are you shouting here?"
你為甚麽在這裏叫喊？
"You nigger, you don't understand any laws."
你這黑鬼，你不懂法律嗎！
He is the chairman of the world high court
他是世界最高法院的首席法官
and this stupid Englishman talking like that.
這個愚蠢的英國人卻對他說這種話
The English are really, in a way,
英國人真是
they are really dumb people
啞的
because their intelligence never told,
他們的聰明從不告訴他們
tells them that you are nothing.
是微不足道的
What are you proud of?
他們有甚麽值得自豪？
Such dumb people they are.
這種不懂說話的人
I don't know it might have come frozen
我也不知道是否因為天氣冷
with the cold or anything,
他們凍僵了，又或是其他原因
but they think they are very intelligent.
他們以為自己是最聰明的
Their scholarship was all right,
他們的學術成就還好
but I was amazed that in the beginning of the scholarship
我卻很驚嘆在他們的學術
that they had, they said
剛有點成就時，他們會說
that the black people are like beasts.
黑人像野獸
There are so many books written about it,
很多書籍對黑人都有這種描繪
and they accepted that black people are like beasts
他們視黑人為野獸
while these people were living,
但黑人卻是活生生的
like I don't know what,
我也不知道怎會這樣
at the time when Black were much more advanced.
在那時候，黑人比他們先進
So, this kind of an idea when they have I see here also.
我在這裏也見到他們有這種思維
I can see this that English have,
英國人一樣
they think no end of themselves.
只想著自己
But they don't understand they don't know anything.
卻不知道自己甚麽也不懂
They have no wisdom.
毫無智慧
They lived in India for 300 years.
他們在印度生活了三百年
They never learned anything from India.
卻甚麽也學不到
Can you imagine their wisdom part?
你因此可以想像他們有怎樣的智慧？
Their scholarship,
他們一些人的
some of them,
學術成就
but still ambiguous.
仍然很模糊
Say Bernard Shaw I think was very ambiguous.
就像蕭伯納 (Bernard Shaw)，我認為他是很模糊的
I place him as a very great writer, but ambiguous.
我視他是很偉大的劇作家，但卻很模糊
And then comes the French, God save.
跟著說到法國，天啊
Now how have they denied Shri Krishna
你可以清楚看到法國人是
you can see very clearly in French people.
怎樣否定錫呂‧克里希納
French wanted to become the highest in diplomacy.
法國想在外交方面有最高的成就
They lack diplomacy completely. Useless people.
但卻完全缺乏外交手腕，無用的人
They made our telephone in India the way they have spoiled it.
他們糟蹋印度的電話就如糟蹋自己的電話一樣
So, they started a cult of drinking.
他們開始對喝酒狂熱
Now can you imagine Shri Krishna drinking all these things?
你能否想像錫呂‧克里希納喝酒？
They have a dictionary on drinking on, everything.
他們甚至連「酒字典」也有
There's books after books written.
還一本接一本的書籍講述喝酒
I mean you imagine how could any evolved people
我的意思是你想像不了
accept this kind of a nonsensical culture
任何已經進化的人
that you must know what to drink,
會接受這種你必須知道該喝甚麽酒
what to buy, what to put in,
該買甚麽酒，怎樣的平底
what sort of a tumblers to be put?
無腳酒杯盛怎樣的酒的荒唐文化
They are all tumblers, nothing but tumblers I think.
他們全是無腳的酒杯，我認為他們只是無腳的酒杯
How could they accept such a thing
他們怎能接受
which is so stupid, is a social acceptance?
這麽愚蠢的文化,這是受社會接受嗎？
Prostitution is another social acceptance.
另一種廣為社會接受的是娼妓
Morality-wise they have really denied completely
道德上他們完全
the principal of Shri Krishna.
否定錫呂‧克里希納原則
The way they have been ruining their people
他們那種摧毀自己的人民
and to beat up everything is racialism.
痛打一切的行為是種族主義
Can you think that for the skin you separate people?
你有否想過膚色可以分隔人？
On the contrary I would say the Black,
相反，我必須要說黑人
especially in India; they're much more evolved
特別是在印度的黑人
than all the white skins put together,
他們比所有白種人
because they have wisdom.
的總和還要進化,因為他們有智慧
They are wiser people.
他們是有智慧的人
But these white skins,
但那些白種人
they are going to - I mean,
我們持續…我的意思是
how did they get America also?
他們怎樣得到美國？
They dominated so much, they conquered it,
他們是那麽好支配，他們是佔領了美國
they settled down there.
才能安居下來
You saw yesterday, from Sierra Nevada you saw
昨天，你看到內華達山脈(Sierra Nevada)的人
how people believed in wisdom and how they lived.
是怎樣相信智慧，怎樣過生活
They took away all their lands.
他們卻佔領了他們的土地
Everybody, you see, is now nicely the owner of America.
你現在看到每一個美國人都是業主
How? You are squatters.
怎會這樣？你們攀山涉水而來
You came from another country,
來自另一個國家
killed thousands and thousands of people
卻毫不因殺害成千上萬的人
without feeling guilty about it.
而內疚
That means they are not even human beings.
這表示他們甚至不是人類
And nicely settled as Americans.
卻以美國人自居而安居下來
I don't know how this word 'America' has come,
我不知道美國(America)這個字的來源
but if it means "amar" they are not.
若它代表「amar」，它不是
It means "a mericas" they are not.
若它代表「a mericas」，也不是
Both ways I don't know how this word has come
無論是否這兩種解釋，我也不知道這個字是從何而來
and some sort of a, uh, meaning they attach to it,
是某些「a」，意思是他們依附它
but their intellect grew much more.
智力卻更能增長
Why? Again, because of money orientation.
為甚麽？同樣是因為金錢取向
I don't understand economics
我不懂經濟
and the way they have made this economics from their,
他們腦袋裏的
yarns which came out of their heads
冒險故事登陸全球
has landed all the countries into recession,
令全球經濟衰退
all kinds of fraud and also mafia.
出現各種欺騙手段，還有黑手黨
That is the outcome of this so-called economics they have.
這就是他們所謂的經濟
Sahaj economics is very different.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的經濟卻截然不同
We are not bound by all these nonsensical ideas
我們不受這些經濟潮流的
that are prevalent as economics.
荒唐念頭束縛
Is nothing but exploitation.
這些只是剝削
Is marketing.
是市場學
Is how to impress people,
只為令人留下印像
how to sell things,
只為推銷貨品
how to do this, how to do that.
只為做這些，做那些
All this is nothing but, I would say,
所有這些，我可以說
financial aggressiveness.
都是經濟的侵略
What about Shri Krishna?
錫呂‧克里希納又怎樣？
He was the king and He lived like a king.
祂是國王，祂活得像國王
But also, He lived in a very humble abode
祂住在Gokul
in Gokul.
一處簡陋的地方
He was not attached.
毫不執著
So the first thing is that the way they're attached to money,
他們最先執著於金錢
any justification for getting money is all right.
任何可以賺錢的行為都沒有不妥
Once we went to a hotel in India.
有一次我們來到印度的酒店
So we had some American friends
與一些美國朋友一起
and as usual, I mean, you can't eat like Americans can,
就如平常一樣，我的意思是你不能吃得像美國人
you know. Is, Indians can't compete.
你要明白，印度人沒法與他們相比
Can eat a lot.
他們可以吃得很多
So they were eating, eating, eating and,
他們在吃，不停的吃
but we couldn't cope with them, really, to be very frank,
我們沒法與他們相比，真的，老實說
I mean, we're no good.
是我們不好
After some time they said, "Have you finished?" I said, "Yes."
一段時間過後，他們說︰「你吃完了嗎？」我說︰「吃完了。」
"All right..." they called the waiter,
「好吧」他們叫服務員
"Pack this out." I said, "What?
「把這些包好。」我說︰「甚麽？
Want to pack this for what?" "We paid for it."
為甚麽要包好這些食物？」「是我們付錢的。」
"So you paid for it, but I mean...In India nobody will eat a food
「你付錢！但我…在印度，沒有人會
which somebody else has eaten."
吃別人吃過的食物。」
"No, you pack it."
「不，你拿走它。」
And they had no shame about it;
他們完全沒有因此感到羞恥
so shameless. I said.
不知羞恥。我說︰
"We don't do this in India."
在印度我們不會這樣做
Said, "Why not?" I said,. "These are bad manners."
他們說︰「為甚麽？」我說︰「這是沒禮貌的。」
"But we've paid for it.
我們已經付了錢
Once you've paid for it then there is no bad manners."
付了錢，拿走它就不是不禮貌。」
I said, "Ah, we don't want this to pack."
我說︰「啊！我們不想拿走。
"We'll have it. We'll have it in the night.
「那麽，我們拿走它吧，我們會在晚上吃
We'll have it in the evening."
又或在黃昏時吃。」
I was surprised that such miserly people
這種吝嗇的人在說
are saying that they are very rich
他們很富有時
and they think no end of themselves; extremely miserly.
我感到很驚訝，他們只想著自己，極之吝嗇
Americans are superficially nice, I must tell you.
美國人表面極友善，我必須告訴你
On my experience is they are not like English
我的經驗是他們不會像英國人那樣
that they look down upon everyone.
看不起人
No you don't feel that way with them.
他們不會這樣
But they are very superficial.
但他們卻很膚淺
You give them ten presents; they won't even give you one.
你送他們十件禮物，他們也不會回贈一件
They have no sense at all; no shame about it.
完全沒有判斷力，沒有羞恥之心
Why? Because the whole thing is, 'we paid for it'.
為甚麽？原因是︰「我們付錢的。」
I mean you go to any place,
我的意思是當你走到任何地方
any restaurant there or anything, you'll be amazed.
任何餐廳，你會很驚訝
They pack things for you
在美國，任何吃剩的食物
if something is left over in America.
他們都會拿走
They do.
他們都會
To that extent they can go in their miserliness
他們吝嗇的程度，已經到達
without any shame about it.
毫無羞恥心
And miserliness is out of Sahaja Yoga.
吝嗇並非來自霎哈嘉瑜伽
You cannot be miserly.
你不能吝嗇
You have to be generous.
你必須慷慨
You have to be giving.
你必須給予
You have to feel for others.
你必須能感受別人的感受
Is this the only way we can express ourselves.
這是你唯一可以表達自己的途徑
All this generosity
慷慨不是要
is not to create a big sort of a hero out of you.
把你創造成大英雄
But the worst and the worst and the worst is the Hollywood.
差勁之中的最差勁要算是荷利活的
Is the film industry.
電影工業
Under the name of industry you can do anything.
以工業的名義，你可以為所欲為
Now this Hollywood is creating such horrible films,
荷利活在製造這種可怕的電影
but the worst is that they get awards for these worst films.
最差的是他們竟然因這些影片而獲獎
There's one film they showed, I've not seen, I can't see it.
有一齣電影，我不曾看過，我不想看
They told Me that a man is a cannibal
他們告訴我有一個男人是食人族
and he is eating the flesh of human beings
他吃人肉
and they have shown but they enjoy.
在吃人肉時他還表現得很享受
Very, very famous. Apart from that,
這是一齣非常，非常有名的電影。還有
not only famous, but they got awards for the best film,
這齣電影不單有名，還得了最佳電影獎
the best actor, the best...
最佳演員奬，最佳…
You must get a director from there
你必須把這個導演捉拿來
and make him eat the flesh of human beings.
要他吃人肉
It's the only way, I think this horrible thing...
只能這樣做，我想這是可怕的…
Then they are producing other pictures.
他們還製作另一些影像
I've seen another one for a short time
我看過很短的一段
where they shows all dead bodies hanging you see.
掛著很多死屍
Horrible!
很可怕！
Why these people like to see such horrible things?
為甚麽他們喜歡看這種可怕的東西？
What is their character?
他們有怎樣的個性？
Where have they gone?
他們何去何從？
Why do they enjoy things which no human being
為甚麽他們享受
who is a human being will enjoy?
有人性的人不享受的？
And then it goes further.
更甚的是
Their halloween business - I saw a film,
萬聖節的生意。我看過一齣電影
I said, "My God." This is a hell in which
我說︰「天啊！這是地獄
they thought it was like the wrath of Shri Krishna.
就像在錫呂‧克里希納的憤怒裏。」
So it was Krishna consciousness I think
是克里希納的意識
that was working there.
在運作
There are thousand and one things which can shock you in America,
在千件事中，有一件事在美國令你震驚
and also in England, also in Europe.
也在英國，還有在歐洲
I thought Austria was something better,
我想奧地利還好一點
but in Austria when you walk on the road
但在奧地利，若你在
in the night after the program
在靜坐班之後，晚上走在路上
you must take darshan of many horrible women there on the way.
你必須拿了很多可怕女人給你的東西
I mean this is no where...
我的意思是沒有一處…
you know they're, we're forced into it.
你要明白，我們是迫著走在這路上
And they can't do anything about it
她們也控制不了
as if it's a matter of right, you see,
就像這是她們的權利
what you call that of human right
去注視這種女人
to see such women,
是你宣稱的人權
and human right for these women to be on the street.
她們站在路上也是她們的人權
All horrible things are happening around,
一切可怕的事情在我們周遭發生著
so Sahaja Yogis have to equip themselves much more
因此霎哈嘉瑜伽士，必須要更加
with a Shri Krishna's principle.
以錫呂‧克里希納原則來裝備自己
The first principle is communication.
最先的原則是溝通
First principle is how you communicate with others.
你怎樣與別人溝通
Start it at home with your children,
從家中開始，你的孩子
with your wife, with your husband,
你的妻子，你的丈夫
how you communicate.
你怎樣與他們溝通
Are you gentle?
你是否溫和？
Are you kind?
是否仁慈？
Are you dominating, aggressive?
是否好支配，好侵略？
Just try to find out.
請去找找看
It can go to any limit this aggressiveness,
這種侵略可以是無盡頭的
either of the women or of the men.
可以是來自女人也可以是來自男人
Here more women I must say, I'm sorry to say.
在這裏，我必須要說，多數來自女人,很抱歉這樣說
But in my experience I've seen the women are very dominating.
以我的體驗，我看到女人是非常專橫
In India men are extremely dominating,
在印度，則是男人極度專橫
but here I find the women are.
但在這裏，我發覺專橫的是女人
Now the basics
作為人類，最基本的
as human beings should have good manners.
是要有好的態度
I don't find good manners,
在這裏我卻找不到好的態度
except that they wear good dresses, maybe the...
除了他們穿得很好外，或許…
they might be wearing those special type of dresses and all that.
他們穿一些特別的服裝
All manners are in dresses,
好的態度只反映在衣服上
but when there are people together
但當他們在一起
they talk nothing but scandal.
卻只談醜聞
I mean, unbearably, horrible scandals they discuss.
我的意思是這是令人受不了，他們討論的是可怕的醜聞
This is something one has to understand
你們要明白
that Shri Krishna never talked of scandals.
克里希納從不談誹聞
How can this, the country of Shri Krishna
怎會這樣，這個錫呂‧克里希納的國家
and all other these European countries
還有其他歐洲國家
are just very equipped with all the scandals of the world?
竟然以全世界的醜聞來裝備自己？
I just can't understand what is the interest
我就是不明白為甚麽大家
people have in the scandals.
對醜聞那麽感興趣
So to top it all is your media
醜聞幅蓋全部的媒體
which is absolutely anti Shri Krishna
這是絕對違反錫呂‧克里希納
because they have to make money.
因為他們想榨取金錢
It's such a hand in glove business
這是一種互相勾結的生意
that the people like to hear all this nonsense,
人們喜歡聽這些荒唐的事情
so they have scandals in the newspaper.
報章因此才刊登醜聞
At least about thirty years back
三十年前
you could never hear such a thing
你不會聽到這些
and all such books were completely banned.
有關這些的書籍都是禁書
And now, suddenly, the whole thing has flowered so well
但現在，醜聞卻忽然興盛起來
that any magazine, anything you take,
任何雜誌，任何你接觸到的事物
and you can't understand
你不明白他們
what are they preaching.
在鼓吹甚麽
They are preaching the cult of destruction completely.
他們在鼓吹禮教的完全滅亡
And people take it, and like it, and work it out.
大家卻接受它，喜歡它，去成就它
They are using the women for their own purpose
他們利用婦女去達到自己的目的
and stupidly women accept it.
愚蠢的女人卻接受
Of course they dominate,
當然他們也好支配
on one side feel very happy that they are dominating.
有人因為能控制別人而高興
There was a lady who was boasting in one magazine
一個女士在雜誌裏，自誇她
that she has had four hundred men in her life.
一生中有四百個男人
Can you imagine?
你能想像嗎？
Now there is no place for hell for such a woman even.
就算是地獄，也沒有位置安置這個女人
Where will you put such a woman there?
你可以怎樣安置這個女人？
Now I don't know; that's another problem.
我也不知道，這是另一個問題
So this movement,
所以這種運動
which is absolutely against the principle of dharma
是絕對違反正法
and of communication.
以及溝通的原則
Now how you must communicate
現在該怎樣溝通？
decently,
以正派的
with very tender
溫柔的
and very beautiful mannerism
美好的態度
you have to talk to another person,
與別人說話
talk to other Sahaja Yogis,
與霎哈嘉瑜伽士說話
talk to anyone,
與每一個人說話
is in a very sweet manner you should talk.
你必須以很親切的態度說話
I do not mean the French style, you see,
我不是指法國式
bending your body and all artificial stuff. Not that.
把身體彎曲，以各種虛假的態度，不是這樣
I'm saying that if you are naturally talking to somebody,
我是說若你要自然的與人說話
you should talk with decent language,
言詞必須是正派的
with decency, with humility
態度要莊重亦謙卑
and need not go on jabbering all the time
不是吱吱喳喳
and talking too much. There's no need.
說話太多，不是這樣
But, on the contrary,
相反
this was the style was Shri Krishna.
這只是錫呂‧克里希納的風格
In short, His power was madhurya;
簡單來說，祂的力量是madhurya
is the sweetness, like the honey.
是甜美，像蜂蜜一樣
When you are worshiping Shri Krishna
當你敬拜錫呂‧克里希納
you have to know that you must talk
你必須知道，
in a manner that will please another person.
要以令人愉快的態度與別人說話
So, while talking to anyone
與人交談
you can talk very sweetly,
態度要很可親
very nicely and in a way which will please that person,
很友善，令人愉快
not to provoke,
而不會激怒人
not to say things which are hard.
也不要說些令人不安的話
But some people have a habit
有些人習慣
of saying all the time something which is very provoking,
說些激怒人的話
which is not at all good.
這是絶對不好的
But some people are,
另一些人
when it comes to their business are very sweet,
在談生意時，說話很體貼
but when it comes to something else they are very harsh.
但說到其他事情時，卻說話苛刻
We have a Jain community in India.
在印度，有耆那教(Jain)的社區
I've seen many Jains.
我曾經見過很多耆那教教徒，
When they are for their business
當說到生意時，
they're the sweetest you could know,
他們是你所認識最和藹可親的人
but when it comes to something else
但一說到其他事情
like donating some money or something,
例如捐款等等
they're extremely hard.
他們的話就極之尖酸
They will only donate for stupid things,
他們只會為愚蠢的事情捐款
but not for something sensible.
而不是一些合情理的事情
They'll work for something extremely stupid,
他們亦只為極之愚蠢的目標工作
but never for anything sensible.
而不是為明智的目標
We have another community called as Sindhis.
還有另一個稱為Sindhis的社區
I think they are under the influence of the West.
他們深受西方的影響
Same with the Western people.
與西方人一樣
If you show that you have some business with them,
若他們知道可以與你談生意
suddenly you know, they change.
你會忽然發覺他們變了臉
Suddenly they change. You can't understand
忽然改變了。你不明白
what has happened to this man.
甚麽發生在這些人身上
Or, if they find out you are something in life, they change.
又或他們發現你是活生生的，因此他們改變了
Shri Krishna was just the other way round.
克里希納則完全相反
In His lifetime, He was always a guest of Vidhura
祂常常到Vidhura家中作客
who was the son of a Dhasi, is the servant.
Vidhura是女僕Dhasi的兒子
Maidservant's son was Vidhura, but he was a realized soul.
他是已得自覺的靈
So He used to go to his house,
祂常常到他的家，留在他的家
stay in his house, a very humble abode, Vidhura's,
謙卑的住在他的家
and eat food there, very simple food.
吃哪裏簡單的食物
But He would not go to the palace of Duryodhana.
卻不往在Duryodhana的宮殿裏
The other way round.
我們卻與祂相反
I mean, somebody thinks that you have a palace,
我的意思是若有人知道你擁有一所宮殿
they'll be extremely kind to you, very nice, you know.
他們會對你極之和藹，極之友善
But they say he lives in a hut, then he's nothing.
但若他說是住在小屋裏，他便是微不足道了
It's such a money orientation in subtle way.
以精微的層面來說，這是那麽金錢取向
Shri Krishna never, never cared for money
錫呂‧克里希納從不關心錢
and never bothered about it.
也從不受錢所困擾
You can see His case
充分顯示祂的性格就是這樣
in which He has shown complete detachment
祂那種對王位
about His throne, or His kingdom,
對他的王國
or money part of it.
對金錢的完全不執著
Once you are attached you have all the pangs of money.
當你有執著，你便深受金錢之苦
Naturally, if you are catching hold of a snake
很自然，若你手上拿著一條蛇
you'll always be having the pangs of the snake, don't you?
蛇常常會困擾你，是嗎？
But supposing you are detached.
但若你能不執著
Then the same money you can use.
相同的金錢，你卻可以好好的運用
Once you become slave of that money,
但若你變成錢的奴隸
that money sits on your head.
錢便會控制你
Now, you know very well that to have money
你很清楚，這些日子裏
also is dangerous these days.
擁有錢是很危險的
The whole reaction is building up
反作用是建基於此
and this is where the whole
所有元素
all the elements are reacting against you.
就是這樣向你反擊
You have seen the wisdom of these people from Sierra Nevada,
你們也見過來自內華達山脈的人的智慧
and what they said is true
他們說的話都是真理
that when we try to acquire more money,
當我們想賺更多錢
go on acquiring, go on acquiring
不停的賺錢
and getting a idea in our head,
腦海中滿是錢
then there are looters who come round.
掠奪者便會在附近出現
I think the worst are those
我想最差的要算是
who have got names as entrepreneurs.
以企業家自居的人
For example, they'll say, "Now,
例如，他們說︰「現在
if you have a designer's watch",
你要擁有品牌的手表
then everybody ran for designer's watches.
每個人都追求名牌手表
The other day I went to Italy, no, to Istanbul
前幾天我到意大利，不，是伊斯坦堡
and I found out that the T-shirts are made there
我發現在法國出售的襯衣，原來是哪裏生產的
and sold in France as if they are French. They are not.
但卻像在法國生產一樣，實際卻不是
They are A to Z, they are made in there, which is Istanbul
全部襯衣都是在伊斯坦堡生產
and the name is on that Lacoste,
只是加上如Lacoste等
this that and all that.
各種不同的牌子，人們願意付任何金額的錢
And people pay any amount, but not in Turkey.
去購買這些襯衣，他們實際想買的，不是在土耳其製造的貨品
Whatever surplus is left we can get it for seven pounds.
買剩的貨品，我們都可用七英鎊買到
Now the stupidity is that they can befool you.
愚蠢之處是他們愚弄你
Pierre Cardin, then there's another one,
Pierre Cardin是另一個名牌子
I don't know, Armani - that's in Italy only,
還有的是，Armani吧，這只是在意大利
but in America there are many.
在美國更多
Even, I mean, they come to you,
更甚的是他們自動的找你
to your house.
來到你的房子
England is much worse.
英國更差
They're so unmannerly,
他們很沒禮貌
they'll come to your house for dinner
當他們來你的家吃晚飯
and they'll turn the plate to see where it is made.
會把盤子反轉，看看它在哪裏製造
Really. Openly.
真的，公開地的這樣做
And they'll discuss from where the cutlery has come.
他們還討論餐具是哪裏來的
So, though they think they're very rich,
雖然他們以為自己很富有
stupidly they are being exploited by this kind of a nonsense
但卻愚蠢的受你擁有這類手表
that you have this watch, you have this thing.
你擁有這些東西這種荒唐追求名牌的行為愚弄
Now, in England we have something called Saville Row,
在英國，有一條稱為Saville Row的購物街
so that they put it outside, you know,
他們把它放在外面，你明白嗎
outside the coat - Saville Row.
放在大衣外面
Can you imagine?
你可以想像嗎？
Branded.
有牌子的
See, everything is made into a big ado.
一切都是那麽混亂
So on one side they are very intelligent
一方面，他們很聰明的
to understand this is the business,
知道這是生意
this is the fashion all that.
是潮流
The other side they don't know they are fools,
另一方面，卻不知道自己是蠢人
being befooled all the time by saying
常常因為說這是特別的東西
this is the special thing, that is the special thing
那是特別的東西
and that it has a name and it has, what you call,
這是有牌子的而受愚弄。該怎樣說…
the - a great organization behind it.
是背後有一所大機構
Sahaja Yogis should understand this is all befooling
霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須明白，這些都是騙人的
and stupid thing and they wear,
愚弄人的，但他們卻穿在身上
all of them will wear like that just to show off.
只為炫耀而全都穿得一式一樣
What is it?
這是甚麽？
Why should this impress anyone?
為甚麽會令人留下印象？
Think of it.
試想想
Now, intelligently think why should it impress you,
聰明點想想，為甚麽這些令你留下印象
these befooling things that are going on?
這種愚弄人的東西卻持續著
Nothing special.
它們沒甚麽特別
They are just the same.
都是一式一樣的
They told Me in Istanbul that they make ordinary ones
他們告訴我在伊斯坦堡
and then they put on top of this mark
貨品製造後，再加上這個商標
and the ordinary ones are for, say,
普通貨品的售價
six dollars, so with this thing is for seven dollars.
是六元，有商標的則七元
There's nothing special,
沒有甚麽特別
but this special trickery, I think,
特別的只是這是奸計
is coming from England and America especially
我想是來自英國和美國
maybe also from France, but France are, you know,
特別是美國，或許還有法國，法國人是，你也知道
queer people.
奇怪的人
Now they have something. I showed them today -
我今天向他們展示
So stupidly made thing,
這種愚蠢的製造貨品方式
which cost five hundred pounds,
成本只是五百英鎊
but people accept because they have no wisdom.
但大家都接受，他們都是沒有智慧的
Now see the difference between the intelligence and wisdom.
你們現在都明白聰明和智慧的分別，
Why to show off, first of all
為甚麽要炫耀
and to show off something which has no meaning?
炫耀一些毫無意義的東西？
It cost only one dollar in Turkey to put that thing on
在土耳其，加上這商標的成本只是一元
and stupidly people are showing it.
蠢人卻在炫耀
Is it that we have intelligence,
我們是否只有聰明才智
but which has no divine power?
卻沒有上天的力量？
Anybody can befool you to do what you like.
任何人都可以愚弄你，令你做你喜歡的事情
Now six inches of skirt started.
從六吋的裙子開始
All right, everywhere six inches.
好吧，每一處的裙子都是六吋
You couldn't get one with the seven inches even.
七吋的裙子怎樣也找不到
That's not in the fashion.
這不是走入潮流
That's not in - means 'in' in madhouse?
而是走人瘋人院
Now just look at Shri Krishna's style - so wise,
現在看看克里希納的風格，祂的智慧
witnessing everything,
祂靜觀一切
how He plays around
祂是怎樣玩耍
and how He wins over.
怎樣取勝
Now, supposing He was attached.
若祂執著
He could not have done it.
就不能做到
So to get over this, first of all, you detach yourself from this
要克服執著，首先你要脫離這種
anti-Shri Krishna culture.
反錫呂‧克里希納的文化
It's very important.
這是很重要的
This is the fashion. That is the fashion.
這是潮流，那是潮流
And all these fashions are extremely, extremely destructive.
所有這些潮流是極之，極之富毀滅性
Now, not to put oil in the hair
不要把油塗在頭髮上
and end up with bald heads. All right.
不然最終你會禿頭。好吧
Then there are specialists, you see,
有些專家，你明白
again designers who make wigs, designer's wig.
還有造假髮的設計師，名牌子的假髮
So you carry a wig on your head and write it down, 'designer's.'
你帶上假髮，假髮上寫上名牌設計
My idea is to see
我是要指出
how stupid human beings can become with their intellect.
人類因為他們的聰明，可以變得這麽愚蠢
Today I don't want to describe the qualities of Shri Krishna
今天我不想再描述錫呂‧克里希納的品質
because you know them.
這些品質你們都知道
But how you people have gone away,
在西方，人們卻遠離
in the West, from Shri Krishna's styles,
錫呂‧克里希納的風格
His methods.
祂的處事方法
Whatever He did was to destroy the evil,
祂做的一切都是為了摧毀邪惡
to destroy the negativity
摧毀負面
and to bring forth the joy,
帶來喜樂
which is Ras, He started. "Ras" - Ra is energy with that.
那是Ras，祂開展Ras，Ra是這個能量
The Ras is the energy,
Ras是你擁有的
which you have
能量
and that's how you play the Ras,
這就是你怎樣玩弄能量
with that energy and enjoy.
與能量一起及享受能量
He brought it Holi.
祂令能量變得神聖
Of course now "Holi" can be anything,
當然現在甚麽也是神聖
but very sensible Holy he brought just to express your joy
祂令人知道甚麽才是神聖，只為以令人愉快
in mirthful, playful ways,
開玩笑式來表達你的喜樂
because that was lacking in Shri Rama's life.
因為喜樂是錫呂‧羅摩缺少的
So He said just allow yourself to enjoy,
所以祂說，要讓自己享受
but this was only for Sahaja Yogis.
這只適用於霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Not for others.
不是其他人
Others, you know that they go to the pubs
其他人，你知道他們走進酒吧裏
and what happens. We have a certificate here that
甚麽會發生。我這裏有一張証書
we are very peaceful, very good people, this and that.
証明他們是非常平和，非常好的人
This is what Shri Krishna said
錫呂‧克里希納又說
and has done,
又做的是
that we have to enjoy everything,
我們必須享受一切
but in a dharmic way.
以正法的途徑
We should not be adharmic.
不應不依正法
The Dharma should give you Joy.
正法必須能帶給你喜樂
Otherwise, if you are dharmic, you know what happens,
若你是正義的，你知道甚麽會發生
that you become absolutely austere,
你變得很嚴肅
person, joyless person
毫無喜樂
and sometimes cynical
有時也有點悲觀
because you think others are adharmic and this and that.
因為你以為全都人都是正義的
But Shri Krishna's ways were that you should be mirthful,
錫呂‧克里希納的處事方式是你必須令人愉快
you should be joyful
必須充滿喜樂
and this joy will communicate with others.
這種喜樂要傳播給人
Without this joyous nature you cannot be communicator.
沒有這種喜樂，你不是好的傳播者
But, as you know, when I went to French,
你們都知道，當我到達法國
they told Me, "Mother, you look so joyous,
他們告訴我︰「你看來那麽喜悅
you should tell you are miserable."
你必須告訴人你是不愉快的
I said, "But I am not."
我說︰「我不是。」
"If you don't tell, then they won't believe you."
若你不這樣說，他們不會相信你
I said, "Why?" "Because they are all miserable
我說︰「為甚麽？」「因為他們全都不開心
and they think they are very unhappy people."
他們以為自己很不愉快
So I started my lecture with "Les Miserables"
因此我以「悲慘世界」(Les Miserables)來開始我的講座
and I told them that at every fourth lamppost
我告訴他們，每四支燈柱
you find a prostitute and every tenth one a pub.
就站著一個妓女，每十支燈柱
And I see so many people sitting on the pavement,
就有一間酒吧。我看到很多人坐在人行道上
so I asked them, "Why are they sitting here?"
我因此問他們︰「他們為甚麽坐在這裏？」
Said, "They are waiting the whole world to be destroyed."
他們答︰「他們在等著世界滅亡。」
I said, "Really?" After drinking, these ideas come in,
我說︰「真的嗎？」喝酒後，這些念頭便會出現
that let the whole world be destroyed
就讓整個世界被摧毀吧
because maybe they don't have any more money to go to pubs.
原因或許只是因為他們沒錢到酒吧
I don't know why.
我不知道為甚麽
Now, think their level,
想想他們的層次
just think of their level.
只想想他們的層次
Where are they
他們怎能
compared to you all?
與你們相比？
So He's the one, as Virata,
祂就是那位
puts light into your brain.
把光放進我們腦袋的宇宙大我
In that light you see what is stupid;
在這光中，你看到甚麽是愚昧
what is unwise.
甚麽是沒有智慧
This is the blessing of Shri Krishna.
這是錫呂‧克里希納的恩賜
And He gives you the nirananda
祂給你涅槃(Nirananda)
because if you don't have the light you cannot enjoy
若沒有光，你不能享受思維的喜樂
the joy of your mind
又或你腦袋
or the joy of your brain.
的喜樂
You cannot.
你不能
And it is through His light
是藉由祂的光
that we see
我們才能看到
ourselves as something full of joy
自己是充滿喜樂
and we don't know what to do with it
我們不知道該做甚麽
and how to do it;
該怎樣做
how to express our joy;
怎樣表達我們的喜樂
how to express our feelings.
怎樣表達我們的感受
Because it's too much.
因為這是太多了
This another fashion to say, "It's too much."
另一種潮流說︰「太過了。」
Anything you tell them," Mother,it is too much."
任何事情你告訴母親︰「這是太過了。」
Because the brain is full of nonsense,
因為腦袋充滿荒唐
so you tell them anything, nothing can go in their heads.
無論你告訴他們甚麽，他們也聽不進耳
"It's too much."
「這太過了。」
So the wise person,
所以有智慧的人
as Shri Krishna is,
就如克里希納
wisest of wise,
祂是智慧中的智慧
He's the source of wisdom,
是智慧的源頭
has to be Stitha Pragya.
必須變成Stita Pragya
Means he has to be in balance,
意思是祂必須處於平衡
he has to be in dharma
處於正法
and, above that,
更重要的
he has to be in Joy.
是處於喜樂
Now, you are not only in joy, but you know the truth.
現在，你不單處於喜樂，還知道真理
You know the absolute truth.
知道絕對的真理
And this absolute truth
這絕對的真理
is the one that makes you understand
令你明白甚麽是對
what is right, what is wrong and you develop your wisdom,
甚麽是錯，你要發展的是智慧
not your intellect so much.
不是過多的聰明才智
You then see your intellect misbehaving sometimes,
那麽，你便看到，有時，你的聰明怎樣愚弄你
telling you negative ideas,
怎樣告訴你一些負面的念頭
sometimes too much of aggressive ideas.
還給你一些挑釁性的念頭
You can become a witness, "sakshi",
你變成旁觀者，「sakshi」
and that's why Shri Krishna has said,
這是錫呂‧克里希納說的︰
"I am the sakshi of the whole world,
我是全世界的sakshi
the witness of the whole world."
世界的旁觀者
See, you can go on talking about Him,
看，你可以不停的在說祂
but what we have to see, where are we going wrong
我們要看到的是當我們犯錯
and how can Shri Krishna save us?
錫呂‧克里希納可以怎樣拯救我們？
Not by singing, "Hari Rama, Hari Krishna", like that.
不是唱誦︰「Hari Rama，Hari Krishna。」(羅摩萬歲，克里希納萬歲)
By becoming, day by day, wiser person.
不是這樣，不是日日夜夜這樣唱誦，就可以變成有智慧的人
Wisdom gives you definite ideas as to how you have to be.
智慧令你清楚的知道自己該怎樣做
If there is still this thing going on.
若這種事情仍然持續
See, in the Western way they show like this.
你看看，在西方，他們是這樣的，當你問他們︰
Ask them, "How are you?"
「你好嗎？」「我就像這樣。」
"I'm like this." Means what?
「我就像這樣。」甚麽意思？
"Like this."
像這樣
If that is still there,
若你仍是這樣
then Shri Krishna is not awakened,
表示克里希納仍未被喚醒
but if it is that you know what it is,
若你知道這是甚麽
you'll have the same smile as Shri Krishna had.
你便擁有錫呂‧克里希納同樣的笑容
I know. I know that.
我知道，我是知道的
Now we have to understand that our Vishuddhi
我們要知道自己的喉輪
has to be all right.
必須妥當
I get Vishuddhi because I know what it is.
我認識喉輪，因為我知道它代表甚麽
This is America, should be all right,
是美國，美國必須妥當
otherwise My Vishuddhi will never be all right. I think so.
否則我的喉輪永遠也不會妥當，我是這樣認為的
But for Vishuddhi,
至於喉輪
there are so many things we have in Sahaja Yoga
在霎哈嘉瑜伽有太多的事情
which very few people do.
是很少人會做的
At least if you Sahaja Yogis keep your Vishuddhi all right,
就算只是少數的霎哈嘉瑜伽士保持他們的喉輪妥當
I'll be much better off.
我也會好得多
But you never try to keep your Vishuddhi all right.
你們卻從不保持喉輪妥當
Continue with it. Continue with it.
仍然繼續這樣
Even the president of America
就算是美國總統的喉輪
has the worst Vishuddhi I've ever seen,
也是我見過最差的
so you can imagine what good is he going to do.
你可以想像他能有怎樣的作為
What wisdom will he have?
怎樣的智慧？
Now you are a new race,
你們現在是新的族群
blessed by the Divine,
得到上天的祝福
and you have Shri Krishna within yourself awakened.
你內裏的錫呂‧克里希納已經被喚醒
In His own glory, in His own light,
在祂的榮耀裏，在祂的光裏
you should know what is to be done.
你必定知道甚麽是該做的
One must communicate.
我們必須溝通
That you have to do,
你必須去做
but what I've seen that people don't even meditate.
但我卻看到人們甚至不靜坐
Even if they meditate,
就算他們靜坐
they don't want to communicate.
也不想溝通
And sometimes when they communicate,
有時當他們溝通
they think they have become Gods.
他們以為自己已經變成神
It's very difficult.
這是很困難的
Human beings is very
人類是一種
difficult commodity to handle.
非常難應付的商品
You have to communicate with complete humility
你必須如錫呂‧克里希納那樣
the way Shri Krishna did.
以謙卑的態度去溝通
In His ras,
在他的力量裏
He spread the energy of Radha
他把羅陀(Raddha)的力量
into all these people by holding hands.
散發給緊握雙手的人
So His childhood where He killed so many people
所以在祂孩提時殺了的很多人的那些事
and did all that is over.
已經結束
Then even His adulthood,
在祂成長後
where He had to kill His own uncle, is also over.
祂殺了自己的叔父這事亦已經結束
So He becomes the king.
祂成為國王
When He becomes the king then what does He do?
當祂成為國王後，祂做了些甚麽？
Is to communicate.
就是去溝通
Most of His,
祂大部分的品質
expressions of His qualities
都在祂成為
are seen after He became the king.
國王之後顯現出來
Before that He was busy killing,
在此之前，祂忙於殺戮
one after another, all these horrible people.
一個接一個，殺死可怕的人
After that He built,
之後，他建立
built up people.
建立人
He built Dwarika and
建立Dwarika
He tried to communicate
嘗試與人
with people.
溝通.
Now your duty is to build up yourself
你們現在的責任是建立自己
and to communicate with others
與別人溝通時
with all the sweetness, madhurya of Shri Krishna,
態度要像錫呂‧克里希納那麽和藹，那麽madhuri
all the beauty of Shri Krishna,
那麽美麗
with full understanding
對身邊各種愚昧的
as to what stupid things are going round and around.
事情完全理解
Once you understand that,
因為你變得有智慧
you'll not take it because you will become wise
你明白你不會接受
enough not to take to all these nonsensical things
不會接受
that are going on.
荒唐的事情
And it is so much,
真的太多了
I mean, I, in this lecture, I cannot tell you,
我的意思是在這個講座裏，我不能告訴你一切
but now if you become the witness of the whole thing
若你變成旁觀者
you'll see what is happening.
你便看到甚麽在發生
Now we have to stop them from going to Hell.
現在我們要阻止他們進入地獄
And we have to really develop a very, very good personality
我們為此必須發展一種非常，非常好的霎哈嘉瑜伽士的品格
of a Sahaja Yogi. All of you.
我指的是你們全部人
Now, there are many marriages that take place,
現在很多人結婚
then suddenly they decide to divorce.
但忽然他們決定離婚
Divorce is allowed in Sahaja Yoga,
霎哈嘉瑜伽是容許離婚的
but this American style of nonsense
雖然我不想有這種
I don't want to have.
美國式的荒唐
Women are can be very dominating.
婦女可以是非常專橫
One fellow ran away to Russia.
有人逃跑到蘇聯
They have no idea of a marriage.
他們對婚姻完全沒有任何概念
They don't know how to work it out.
他們不懂怎樣令婚姻成功
All the sweetness of the marriage is finished.
若丈夫是專橫，
If the husband is dominating,
或妻子是專橫
the wife is dominating,
美滿的婚姻便完蛋了
this happens, then you divorce.
若丈夫或妻子是這樣，最終必定是離婚收場
What is the achievement?
這是甚麽的成就？
So we have to work out
所以我們必須內在的成就一切
everything within us because we are conditioned,
因我們有制約
we are in an atmosphere.
我們在氛圍裏
I would request all of you
我請你們嘗試理解
to try to understand these subtleties
錫呂‧克里希納品格上
of Shri Krishna's personality.
的精微
Try to become like that
嘗試變得
extremely peaceful,
極之平和
extremely kind, tender, helpful.
極之仁慈，極之溫柔，樂於助人
And in humility,
還有非常謙卑
He had no consciousness of money.
祂對金錢
Nothing.
完全沒有任何意識。
And also, as you know, He was a dark person
你們也知道，祂有陰暗的一面
for some reason,
是因某些原因
but the way He led his life
但祂一生
should be an example for us.
卻是我們的榜樣
I'm sure, now, when you go back to your countries
我可以肯定，當你現在回到你的國家，
you'll see all this nonsense.
你會看到這些荒唐。
Please note it down.
請記錄下，
Write it down what these nonsensical people are doing
寫下這些荒唐的人所做的事情，
and send it over to Me.
把寫下的寄給我吧
That's what it is.
就是這樣
So today is the puja of Shri Krishna.
今天是錫呂‧克里希納的崇拜
I need not tell you how many qualities He has, as I told you,
我不需要告訴你祂擁有甚麽品質
but the greatest quality He has that
讓我告訴你
He is the doctor of doctors.
祂最偉大的品質是祂是醫生中的醫生
Now, in His name you will know how many qualities He has
以祂之名，你會知道，
and you will understand.
你會明白祂擁有多少品質
Try to understand that
嘗試去明白我們也應該
we have to have these qualities within us also.
內裏擁有這些品質
Whatever qualities are described or said,
別人描繪或談論祂的任何品質，
try to see how many we have.
請看看自己擁有多少這些品質。
That's the way the introspection will start.
內省就是這樣開始
Once you start introspecting yourself
當你開始內省
and understanding yourself,
瞭解自己
the wisdom will grow - not by seeing faults in others,
智慧便會增長，不是只著眼別人的缺點
putting blames on others, but on yourself.
只責備別人，而是看著自己
That is how the things will work out.
事情就是這樣成就的
Though Krishna didn't have to do that because
克里希納不需要這樣做
He was Sampurna, He was complete.
因為祂是sampurna，祂是完全的
But we have to do all this
但我們卻要這樣做
to see that we also become complete.
以令自己也變得完全
Thank you very much.
很感謝你們
May God bless you all.
願神祝福你們
There's another point I wanted to mention about Sahaja Yogis,
我想說說霎哈嘉瑜伽士的另一點
that we introduce classical Indian music for you people,
我們向你們推介印度音樂
because I think it helps for vibrations.
因為我認為對能量有幫助
But as the nature is of western people,
西方人的特質是當他們接受任何事物
anything they take up they must go to the utilmate end
他們都必須走向極限
'til they are completely lost.
直至完全迷失
So what I find now all of them are buying tapes.
所以我現在發現，他們不停的購買錄音帶
Some tapes ...
不停的買……
Now some of them are buying tapes, I was surprised,
一些人購買錄音帶，我很驚訝
of very unknown people, just mad.
購買名不經傳的錄音帶，像瘋子一樣
Once I was traveling with a lady in America,
一次我與一位女士一起出門到美國
was a disciple of Muktanand.
她是Muktanand的門徒
She said, "I have a very nice tape," and she played the,
她說︰「我有一個很好的錄音帶。」她播放那錄音帶
the, lecture of Muktanand.
是Muktanand的講話
Rajneesh's people will play the lecture of Rajneesh.
Rajneesh的信徒則播放Rajneesh的講話
But here now they've all gone to one side,
這裏的人
so this one, that one,
都偏向一面
all kinds of music they have got.
他們想取得各種音樂
Tomorrow, we start
明天
telling you that you must understand Indian dancing,
若我們告訴你必須懂印度舞蹈
so all my videos will be replaced by Indian dancing
印度舞蹈便會取代
from A to Z.
我的所有錄影帶
You are Sahaja Yogis.
你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
It's all right, I am also fond of music,
這樣做沒有問題，我也喜歡音樂
but it's not the way.
但不是這樣的
What is the main thing of your life?
你生命中最重要的是甚麽？
And I was surprised how people are lost in the music.
我對人們怎樣在音樂中迷失感到很驚訝
I mean there should be some occasion.
我的意思是必定有某些時機
They're all already in another world with the music.
他們在另一個世界裏享受音樂
Don't do these things.
不要這樣做
You go to extremes of everything.
對一切你都走向極端
That's not proper, even pujas, anything,
這是不正常的，甚至是崇拜
you go to extremes.
一切的事情，你都走向極端
To go to extremes, you won't be in the center.
走向極端，你不在中央
You will not be in the place of Shri Krishna,
你不能身處你必須身處的
where you have to be.
錫呂‧克里希納的領域
On the contrary, you will be
相反
just in another imaginary world.
你仍處於虛幻的世界
So, as a matter of habit we create a world like that;
我們慣於創造各種這樣的世界
somebody has music world;
一些人有音樂世界
somebody has dancing world;
一些人有舞蹈世界
another one has,
另一些人有另一些世界
world, I've seen with Sahaja Yogis who think
我曾經見過一些霎哈嘉瑜伽士
no end of themselves.
只想著自己
"We have a special relationship with Shri Mataji."
「我與錫呂‧瑪塔吉有特別的關係。」
Is a very common thing.
他們常常這樣說，
But I cannot have any special relationship.
實際上我不可能與任何人有特別的關係
Sorry,
很抱歉
nobody has any special relationship with Me.
沒有人能與我有任何特別的關係
This I would like to tell you very clearly,
我必須清楚的告訴你們
and you should not claim that,
不應這樣宣稱
and then become, some people say, "we are deities."
有些人說︰「我們是降世神祇。」
I mean this is something to be - horrible.
我的意思是這真是可怕
I'll speak for two minutes in Marathi if you don't mind...
若你們不介意，我想以馬拉塔語說兩分鐘
Now I want to talk to the Maharashtrian girls.
我現在想向馬哈拉斯特拉邦的女孩說點話
You have been married here,
你們已經與西方的男子結婚
and have got rich husbands.
他們都很富有
But as soon as you came here
但當你來到這裏
you've started sending money to your parents.
卻開始寄錢給父母
Does this happen in India?
這種事有否在印度發生？
Can you send money to your parents from your in laws' house.
你能否從你的外父母家寄錢給父母
Secondly is ornaments.
第二點是飾物
You've started making a lot of ornaments.
你開始製造大量的飾物
I asked a Sahaja yogi husband
我問一個霎哈嘉瑜伽的丈夫
why don't you buy a shirt for yourself.
為甚麽不為自己買件襯衫
He said, "what should I do,
他說負擔不起
my wife is spending all the money on ornaments."
因為妻子把錢都花在購買飾物上
This greed for ornaments does not behove a Sahaja Yogi.
這種對飾物的貪婪不應是霎哈嘉瑜伽士的行為
This is a very serious matter.
這是很嚴重的事
Recently I learnt that all the Indian ladies
最近我發現所有印度女士
have made ornaments after marriage.
在婚後都製造飾物
Thus there is no money left with the husband.
再沒有餘錢留給丈夫
Those husbands who used to support Sahaja yoga before
那些在婚前通常能在金錢上支持霎哈嘉瑜伽的丈夫
are unable to do so after the marriage.
在婚後再沒有能力這樣做了
They have no money left with them.
他們說自己再沒有餘錢
What has happened to you.
發生了甚麽？
you've come here from the land of saints.
要記著你是來自聖人之地
Shivaji Maharaj had a great respect for Shri Saint Tukaram
Shivaji Maharaj對Shri Saint Tukaram極之尊重
and he took some ornaments for his wife.
他拿了一些飾物送給妻子
His wife must be somebody like you,
他的妻子必定像你們那樣
as she immediately accepted the ornaments.
因為她立即接受這些飾物
Why should one be so much fond of ornaments?
為甚麽你們那麽喜歡飾物？
Even being a Goddess I am not fond of ornaments,
就算身為女神的我，也並不喜愛飾物
then why should you be so fond of them?
你們為甚麽那麽喜愛它？
Since they compulsorily offer me that's why I accept.
是因為他們強迫把飾物獻給我
So he gave and she accepted the ornaments,
我才接受。就算她接受飾物
Saint Tukaram came and said,
也說像我們這樣的聖人
"What is the need to have the ornaments for saints like us?"
有甚麽需要擁有飾物？
So he returned back all the ornaments.
他因此把所有飾物退回
Know that you've come here from land of saints
我知道你們都是來自聖人之地
and this attitude of yours is a sign of poorness.
你這種態度是吝惜的徴兆
You've been sending money to your parents
把錢寄給父母
and I cannot explain to you how far this has gone.
我也不知怎樣向你解釋，這是太過分了
You've not come here to misbehave like this.
你來到這裏不是要有這種不當的行為
You've come here to help Sahaja Yoga
你是來幫助霎哈嘉瑜伽
and not for making ornaments.
不是來製造飾物
If you do them once in a while it's all right
若你只是偶然這樣做還可以
but if you put all the attention on ornaments
但若你把全副精神都放在飾物上
you might lose your husband and he might leave Sahaja Yoga.
你可能失去丈夫，他也可能離開霎哈嘉瑜伽
This would be good deed (meant not good), you will achieve!!
這是你做的好業報
Without My permission henceforth,
自此以後，沒有我的准許
nobody should make any ornaments.
誰人也不能造飾物
We'll have the Pooja now.
讓崇拜開始吧